# **Qunliang Xing**

37 Xueyuan Road Haidian District, Beijing, China ryanxingql@gmail.com https://ryanxingql.github.io

### Introduction

Qunliang Xing received the BEng degree and Honors degree from Beihang University, Beijing, China in 2019. He is currently pursuing the Ph.D. degree at Beihang University, advised by Professor Mai Xu. His research interests include image/video enhancement and coding. He has published several papers in IEEE TPAMI and ECCV, one of which is top 1% highly cited according to the essential science indicators (ESI). He has won two NTIRE championships. His open-source projects have received more than 600 stars. He is awarded the Active Contributor by OpenMMLab. He has won the second place in the Beihang 100m final and the Beihang soccer championship as the school team captain. He is a reviewer for several IEEE transactions including TIP, TMM, TCSVT and JAS.

### Education

Beihang University, Beijing, China Sept. 2019 – Present Ph.D. student School of Electronics and Information Engineering Honors Ph.D. Student Shen Yuan Honors College Beihang University, Beijing, China Sept. 2015 - July 2019 Bachelor of Engineering School of Electronics and Information Engineering Honors Bachelor Shen Yuan Honors College Sept. 2012 - July 2015 Nanshan Foreign Language School, Shenzhen, China Admitted to Beihang University with the highest score in Guangdong Province. High School

#### Selected Publications

[1] DAQE: Enhancing the Quality of Compressed Images by Exploiting the Inherent Characteristic of Defocus Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Xin Deng, Yichen Guo

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2023)

[2] Progressive Training of A Two-Stage Framework for Video Restoration
Qunliang Xing, Meisong Zheng, Minglang Qiao, Mai Xu, Lai Jiang, Huaida Liu, Ying Chen
IEEE/CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops (2022)
Technical report of our winning method in the NTIRE challenge.

[3] DeepQTMT: A Deep Learning Approach for Fast QTMT-Based CU Partition of Intra-Mode VVC Tianyi Li, Mai Xu, Runzhi Tang, Ying Chen, Qunliang Xing IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (2021)

[4] Patent CN111415311: Resource-saving Image Quality Enhancement Model Mai Xu, Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan China National Intellectual Property Administration (2020)

[5] Early Exit Or Not: Resource-Efficient Blind Quality Enhancement for Compressed Images Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Tianyi Li, Zhenyu Guan European Conference on Computer Vision (2020) [6] MFQE 2.0: A New Approach for Multi-Frame Quality Enhancement on Compressed Video

Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan, Mai Xu, Ren Yang, Tie Liu, Zulin Wang

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2019)

Highly cited paper (Top 1%) by Essential Science Indicators (ESI).

## Work Experience

Reviewer Feb. 2021 – Present

**IEEE Journals and Conferences** 

• ĬEEE TIP, IEEE TMM, IEEE TCSVT, IEEE/CAA JAS, IEEE ICME

Research Intern Dec. 2021 – Present

Tao Technology, Alibaba Group

• Video quality enhancement for Taobao Live.

• Winning two championships and one runner-up in the NTIRE 2022 challenge.

# Participant in Tencent Rhino-bird Open-Source Training Program July 2021 – Sept. 2021

Tencent

• Selected among the top 127 out of 1,800+ candidates.

# Mentor of Undergraduates Oct. 2020 – Oct. 2021

Shen Yuan Honors College, Beihang University

• Awarded the Shen Yuan Excellent Mentor (Top 9/36).

# Teaching Assistant Sept. 2020 – Jan. 2021

Beihang University

• Introduction to Machine Learning.

Research Intern Dec. 2018 – Dec. 2019

2012 Lab, Huawei

- Video quality enhancement for HW265 codec.
- Improving the RD performance of HW265 by 10%.

### Awards & Honors

Two Championships and One Runner-up		
NTIRE Challenge on Super-Resolution and Quality Enhancement of Compressed	Video 202	2
Glarun Scholarship		
The 14TH Research Institute, China Electronics Technology Group Corporation (	CETC) 202	2
Beihang Outstanding/Merit Student		
Beihang University	2022, 2021, 2018, 201	5
Second Place in the 100m Final		
Beihang Sports Day, Beihang University	202	2
Shen Yuan Excellent Mentor		
Shen Yuan Honors College, Beihang University	202	1
Beihang Excellent Graduate		
Beihang University	201	9
Soccer Championship (Starting CB)		
Beihang Sports Festival, Beihang University	201	7
Shenzhen Merit Student		
Education Bureau of Shenzhen Municipality	201	4